Finding Aid for the Anti-Slavery Pamphlet Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Anti-Slavery Pamphlet Collection
1787-1916
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0731
.42 linear_feet
The Anti-Slavery Pamphlet Collection contains 245 items ranging from 1787 to 1916 that focus on the abolishment of slavery and Reconstruction of the Southern States after the American Civil War. Represented are imprints from Europe as well as the United States, the European publications also discussing situations in Poland and its politics during the 1850’s.
- Swift, Theophilus. The Temple of Folly, in Four Cantos. London: J. Johnson, 1787 (Folder 1)
- Strong, C. The Speech of Governor Strong Delivered Before The Legislature Massachusetts., Given October 16, 1812. Boston: Russell and Cutler, 1812 (Folder 2)
- Address to the Commonwealth of Massachusetts from the House of Representatives. Given July 25, 1812. ( Respecting the resolutions of the Legislature of Massachusetts, refutation of certain insinuations conveyed in the preamble to the Order of the Senate dated June 25, 1812. House of Representatives.) (Folder 3)
- Burgess, Ebenezer (American Colonization Society). Address to the American Society for Colonizing the Free People of Color of the U.S. Washington: Davis and Force, 1818 (Folder 4)
- American Colonization Society. An Essay on the Late Institution of the American Society for Colonizing the Free People of Color of the U.S. Washington: Davis and Force, 1820 (Folder 5)
- Sketch of the Life of John Quincy Adams. The Letters of Tell Addressed to the Editor of the Baltimore American, 1824 (Folder 6)
- Washington, Bushrod. Seventh Annual Report of the American Society for Colonizing the Free People. Washington: Davis and Force, 1824 (Folder 7)
- Hamilton, William. Sermon for the Benefit of the American Colonization Society. Newark: Tuttle and Co., 1825 (Folder 8)
- Patterson, James. A sermon on the Effects of the Hebrew Slavery as Connected with Slavery in this Country. Philadelphia: S. Probasco, 1825 (Folder 9)
- Mr. Trimble of Kentucky, reply to Mr. McDuffie of South Carolina on the Amendment of the Constitution. House of Representatives, 1826 (Folder 10)
- Henry, Patrick. Letter to the Editor of the National Journal, 1826 (Folder 11)
- Johnson, Walter. Thomas Jefferson and John Adams. Philadelphia: Clark and Raser, 1826 (Folder 12)
- Sprague, Peleg. Eulogy on John Adams and Thomas Jefferson, Pronounced in Hallowell. Hallowell, 1826 (Folder 13)
- A collection of addresses, squibs, songs, etc, and The Political Mountebank. England: Preston, 1826 (Folder 14)
- Clay, Henry. Speech at Noble’s Inn Lexington, Given July 12, 1827 (Folder 15)
- An Examination of the civil Administration of Governor [Andrew] Jackson in Florida. National Intelligencer, June 21, 1828 (Folder 16)
- Discours Pronounces Dans La Séance Publique Tenue Par L’ Academie Francaise Pour la Reception de M. Lebrun. Paris, May 22, 1828 (Folder 17)
- Adams, John Quincy. Correspondence Between J.Q. Adams and Several Citizens of Massachusetts. Boston, Press of October 21, 1828 (Folder 18)
- Geisheim, Karl Wilhelm. Ein Verskuenstlerischer Beitrag. Breslau, 1829 (Folder 19)
- Coxe, Richards S. Address Delivered by Richard S. Coxe before the Mechanics and Other Citizens of Washington, July 1830. Washington D.C. (Folder 20)
- Jackson, Andrew and Eaton, J.H. Letters from the Secretary of the War and the President, March 16, 1830 (Folder 21)
- Mephistopheles. A Review of Mr. Cambreleng’s Report from the Committee of Commerce. Baltimore: Wm. Ogden Niles, 1830 (Folder 22)
- Address of the Managers of the American Colonization Society to the People of the U.S. Washington: James Dunn, 1832 (Folder 23)
- Carey, M. Letters on the Colonization Society and its Probable Results. Philadelphia, June 19, 1832 (Folder 24)
- Polonia; Or, Monthly Reports on the Polish Affairs (No. 1, August 1832, Number IV. November, 1832, Number V. December 1832. London (Folder 25)
- Manifesto of The Polish Nation to Europe; and An Address of the Polish Refugees in France to the British House of Commons. London: The Literary Association of the Friends of Poland, 1832 (Folder 26)
- L’ Autocrate et La Constitution Du Royaume De Pologne. Bruxelles: Place De Louvain, Number 7., 1832 (Folder 27)
- Wright, Elizur Jr. The Sin of Slavery and Its Remedy. New York, 1833 (Folder 28)
- Shepherd M., Howard C., Harper C. Sixteenth Annual Report of the American Society for Colonizing the Free People of Colour of the U.S. Washington: James Dunn, 1833 (Folder 29)
- Southard, S.L. Discourse on the Professional Char. And Virtues of the Late Wm. Wirt. Washington: Gales and Seaton, 1834 (Folder 30)
- Morehead, James T. Fifth Annual Report of the Colonization Society of Kentucky. Frankfort, 1834 (Folder 31)
- Tyson, J.R. Discourse Before the Young Men’s Col. Of Philadelphia. Philadelphia, 1834 (Folder 32)
- Memorial of Ladies of Nashville Praying for an Appropriation of Money to Erect an Asylum for the Education of Destitute Orphan Children. Nashville, 1836 (Folder 33)
- Address to the Citizens of Pennsylvania (from a convention held for the formation of a State Anti-Slavery Society). Philadelphia, 1837 (Folder 34)
- Annual Report of the Young Men’s Colonization Society: Pennsylvania, Read February 22, 1837 (Folder 35)
- King. Speech of Mr. King of Georgia on the Bill Imposing Additional Duties as Depositories in Certain Cases on Public Officers. Delivered September 23, 1837. Washington: Gales and Seaton (Folder 36)
- Proceedings of the Pennsylvania Convention Assembled to Organize a State AntiSlavery Society at Harrisburg. Philadelphia, 1837 (Folder 37)
- Anti-Slavery Examiner, The Bible Against Slavery. An Inquiry…Human Rights. New York, 1838 (Folder 38)
- Stephens, A. Address to the Alumni Society of Nashville University. Nashville, T, 1838 (Folder 39)
- Sixth Annual Report of the Colonization Society of the City of New York. New York: Mercein & Post”s Press, 1838 (Folder 39a)
- Colonization Herald and General Register (Volume I, Number 1, and Volume I. Number 2), Jan. Feb, March 1839 (Folder 40)
- Tyler, E.R. Slaveholding a Malum in Se, or Invariably Sinful. Hartford: SS Cowles. (Folder 41)
- Wilkeson, Samuel. Concise History of the Commencement Progress and Present Condition of The American Colonies in Liberia. Washington, D.C., 1839 (Folder 42)
- Right and Wrong in the Anti-Slavery Societies; Seventh Annual Report of the Boston Female Anti-Slavery Society, Presented October 14, 1840. Boston, 1840. (Folder 43)
- The Northern Man With Southern Principles, and The Southern Man with American Principles: or, a View of the Comparative Claims of General Wm. H. Harrison and Martin Van Buren, Esq., Candidates for the Presidency. Washington, 1840 (Folder 44)
- Clarkson, Thomas. Letter to the Clergy of various Denominations, of the Slave States of America, 1841 (Folder 45)
- Halsey, Le Roy J. Address to the Alumni Society of University of Nashville on the Study of Theology. Nashville, 1841 (Folder 45a)
- Republican Banner. Nashville, March 21 1842 (Folder 46)
- Burrell, Robert. First Step in the Ladder to Political Knowledge; or the Young Man’s Catechism. Greenock: W. Johnston and Son, 1843 (Folder 47)
- Tochman, G. Lecture [to] Members of the State Legislatures of New York, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Vermont, Connecticut, Virginia, Ohio, Indiana, and Kentucky, and before the New Jersey State Convention, on the Subject of the Social, Political and Literacy Condition of Poland. Baltimore, 1844 (Folder 48)
- Address Delivered on the Anniversary Of the First Settlement of Ohio. Cincinnati: Morgan and Company, 1844 (Folder 49)
- A Condensed Anti-Slavery Bible Argument. New York: S.W. Benedict, 1845 (Folder 50)
- Young, John, C. Duty of Masters; A Sermon, Preached in the Presbyterian Church In Danville KY: Zimmerman and Barbee, 1846 (Folder 51)
- Address to the People of West Virginia. Shewing That Slavery is injurious. By a Slaveholder in West Virginia. Lexington, 1847 (Folder 52)
- Court Jobbery: or the Black Book of the Palace; Being an Analytical List of All the Pensions Granted by the Queen. London, 1848 (Folder 53)
- Wilkins-Tannehill. The Port Folio; or Journal of Free-Masonry, and General Literature., August, September, and November 1849 (Folder 54)
- Spencer, Ichabod S. Fugitive Slave Law. The Religious Duty of Obedience to Law: A Sermon. New York, 1850 (Folder 55)
- Thornwell, J. H. Rights and Duties of Masters: A Sermon Preached at the Dedication of a Church Erected in Charleston, S.C., for the Benefit and Instruction of the Colored Population. Charleston, SC: Walker and James, 1850 (Folder 56)
- Wilkins-Tannehill. Port Folio; or Journal of Free-Masonry, and General Literature. Nashville: John T. S. Fall, February, March and April 1850 (Folder 57)
- French Soldier, A. Mr. Napoleon Bonaparte. London, 1851 (Folder 58)
- Brief Inquiry Into The Natural Rights of Man, With an Outline of the Principles, Laws, and Institutions by which Liberty, Equality, and Fraternity May Be Realized Throughout the World. London, 1852 (Folder 59)
- Thornwell, J.H. Report on the Subject of Slavery, Presented to the Synod of SC. Columbia, SC, November 6, 1851 (Folder 60)
- The Casket, Devoted to Religion and Literature. Volume III, no IV. S.A Hodgeman: St. Louis, June 1852 (Folder 61)
- 35th Annual Report of the American Colonization Society. Delivered At The Annual Meeting January 20, 1852. Washington: C. Alexander Printing. (Folder 62)
- Ramsay, H.A. Dr. H.A. Ramsay’s Letter to Dr. James Bryan, on the Southern Negro, Etc from the Philadelphia Medical and Surgical Journal. Philadelphia: A. Hughes and Company, 1853 (Folder 63)
- 36th Annual Report of the American Colonization Society, Daniel Webster’s Fall (News- Paper Story), January 29, 1853 (Folder 64)
- Constitution and By Laws Of the Colored Association No I. Of the Friends of Temperance. Knoxville: The Whig Office, 1850 (Folder 65)
- Kossuth, Lajos. Kossuth’s Speeches in the City Hall at Glasgow. London, July 5, 1854 (Folder 66)
- Morell, John Reynell. The Coming Peace. London, 1854 (Folder 67)
- Poland Shall Be Free. Liverpool: Pearce and Brewer, 1854 (Folder 68)
- Letter to the Emperor of the French on the Eastern Question, and the ReEstablishment of the Independence of Poland. London, 1854 (Folder 69)
- The Western Casket, Devoted to Religion and Literature. Volume IV. Number. 9, September. St. Louis, Mo: Reverend S. A. Hodgman, 1854 (Folder 70)
- The North and the South. New York: Office of the Tribune, 1854 (Folder 71)
- Mieroslawski, L. Poland, Russia, and The Western Powers. A Memorial, Historical and Political, Addressed to the British and French Nations. Foreign Affairs Committee, 1855 (Folder 72)
- Hugo, Victor. Visit of the Emperor of the French to England. London: Edward Truelove, 1855 (Folder 73)
- Mieroslawski, L. Poland, Russia, and The Western Powers. A Memorial, Historical, and Political, Addressed to the British and French Nations. Foreign Affairs Committee, 1855 (Folder 74)
- Swietoslawski, Zeno. Speech of a Polish Refugee, at The National. Hall. London 1855. (Folder 75)
- Responsibility of the North in Relation to Slavery. Cambridge: Allen and Farnham, 1856 (Folder 76)
- Martineau, Harriet. History of the American Compromises, A. London: John Chapman, 1856 (Folder 77)
- Quincy, Josiah, Address Illustrative Of the Nature and Power of the Slave States, and the Duties of the Free States. Boston, 1856 (Folder 78)
- The Republican Scrap-Book; Containing The Platforms, and a Choice Selections Of Extracts. Boston: John Jewett and CO, 1856 (Folder 79)
- Ross, F.A. Position of the Southern Church in Relation to Slavery, As Illustrated in a Letter of Dr. F.A. Ross to Rev. Albert Barnes. New York, 1857 (Folder 80)
- Sollemnia Natalicia Regis Augustissimi et Serenissimi Friderici VII… Killiae, 1857 (Folder 81)
- Gooch, D.W. Speech of Hon. D. W. Gooch, of Massachusetts, Delivered in the House of Representatives, March 29, 1858 (Folder 82)
- Seward, William. Freedom In Kansas. March 3, 1858. Washington: Buell & Blanchard (Folder 83)
- Parker, Theodore. The Present Aspect Of Slavery In America and the Immediate Duty of the North: A Speech Delivered Before the Massachusetts Anti-Slavery Convention, January 29, 1858. Boston, 1858 (Folder 84)
- Blair, Frank, Jr. Speech of Honorary Frank P. Blair, Jr., of Missouri, on the Acquisition of Territory in Central and South America to be Colonized with Free Blacks and Held as a Dependency of the United States. Washington: Buell & Blanchard, 1858 (Folder 85)
- Burlingame, Anson. An Appeal to Patriots Against Fraud and Disunion. A Speech of Hon. Anson Burlingame of Massachusetts. Washington: Buell & Blanchard, 1858 (Folder 86)
- Banks, Nathaniel. Address of His Excellency Nathaniel P. Banks to the Legislature of Massachusetts. January 7, 1858. Boston: William White (Folder 87)
- Cheever, George B. Address Delivered in Tremont Temple, Boston Before the American Missionary Association. Boston: John P. Jewett, 1858 (Folder 88)
- Cobbett, James and Thomas Doubleday. Hand-Book for Reformers: Containing Notes Upon Duration of Parliaments, the Suffrage, Mode of Voting, etc. London: Effingham Wilson, April 1859 (Folder 89)
- Massachusetts Public Documents 35-37. Reports of the Guardians of the Chappequiddic, Christiantown, Natick, Troy Indians, September 30, 1859 (Folder 90)
- Massachusetts Document 38. Report of Treasurer of Mashpee to the Governor, 1859 (Folder 91)
- Massachusetts Document 42, Report of the Guardian of the Dudley Indians to the Governor, 1859 (Folder 92)
- Eaton, Mrs. E.M. The Aurora: A Monthly for the Mothers and Daughters of the South and West. Murfreesboro, TN, March, 1859 (Folder 93)
- Williams, Thomas. The Negro in American Politics: A Speech by Thomas Williams Delivered at Lafayette Hall, Pittsburgh, September 29, 1860 (Folder 94)
- Bird, F.W. Review of Gov Banks’ Veto of the Revised Code on Account of Its Authorizing the Enrollment of Colored Citizens in the Militia. Boston: Jewett, 1860 (Folder 95)
- Correspondence Between Lydia Maria Childs and Governor Wise and Mrs. Mason of Virginia. New York, 1860 (Folder 96)
- Child, Maria. The Duty of Disobedience To The Fugitive Slave Act: An Appeal to the Legislators Of Massachusetts. Boston, 1860 (Folder 97)
- A Fresh Catalogue of Southern Outrages Upon Northern Citizens. New York: AntiSlavery Society, 1860 (Folder 98)
- Van Dyke, Henry. The Character and Influence of Abolitionism: A Sermon Preached in the First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn. December 9, 1860. New York: D. Appleton and Company (Folder 99)
- Massachusetts Documents 40-44 Reports on Chappaquiddic, Chistiantown, Natick, Mashpee, Dudley Indians, September 30, 1860 (Folder 100)
- Conway, M.D. Thomas Paine: A Celebration. Cincinnati, 1860 (Folder 101)
- Missing. (Folder 102)
- Zamoyski, L. Poland, A Letter to the Right Honourable Earl Of Ellenborough. London, 1861 (Folder 103)
- Andrew, John. Address of His Excellency John Andrew to the Two Branches of the Legislature of Massachusetts. Boston: William White, Printer to the State, 1861 (Folder 104)
- Public Document 35: Chappequiddic Indians, September 30, 1861 (Folder 105)
- Declaration of Sentiments and Constitution of American Anti-Slavery Society. Philadelphia: Pennsylvania Anti-Slavery Society, 1861 (Folder 106)
- Henry, C.S. Patriotism and the Slaveholders’ Rebellion. An Oration. New York: D. Appleton And Company, 1861 (Folder 107)
- War and Slavery; or, Victory Only through Emancipation. Boston, 1861 (Folder 108)
- Williams, Thomas. Remarks of Honorable Thomas Williams of Allegheny County, in the Legislature of Pennsylvania, on the Joint resolutions Relative to the maintenance of the Constitution and the Union. Pittsburgh: W.S. Haven, 1862 (Folder 109)
- Hill, Matthew Davenport. Charge, Delivered on the Sixth January, 1862, at the Quarter Sessions Held for the Borough of Birmingham. London (Folder 110)
- Mitchell, George. Letters Addressed to Earl Russell, Respecting the Late Events at Warsaw, and in Poland. London: Bickers and Bush, Leicester, 1862 (Folder 111)
- Warrington. A Conspiracy to Defame John Andrew, Being a Review of the Proceedings of Joel Parker, Linus Child and Leverett Saltonstall, at the People’s Convention. Boston, 1862 (Folder 112)
- Smith, Gerrit. Speech of Gerrit Smith on The Country, Delivered at The Cooper Institute. New York: Baker & Godwin, 1862 (Folder 113)
- MacMahon, T.W. Cause and Contrast: An Essay on the American Crisis. Richmond, Virginia, 1862 (Folder 114)
- Public Documents No. 35-39 reports of the Guardians of the Chappequiddic, Christiantown, Natick, Mashpee, and Dudley Indians, September 30, 1862 (Folder 115)
- Laboulaye, Edouard. Why The North Cannot Consent to Disunion. Reprinted From New York Tribune, 1863 (Folder 116)
- Brown, George. The American War and Slavery: Speech of Hon. George Brown at the Anniversary Meeting of the Anti-Slavery Society of Canada. Wednesday, February 3, 1863 (Folder 117)
- Owen, Robert Dale. The Policy of Emancipation: In Three Letters To the Secretary of War, the President of the United States, and the Secretary of Treasury.. Philadelphia, 1863 (Folder 118)
- The Conduct of the War: Report of the Congressional Committee on The Operations of The Army of The Potomac: Causes of Its Inaction and Ill Success, Its Several Campaigns, Why McClellan Was Removed, the Battle of Fredericksburg, Removal of Burnside. New York: The Tribune Association, 1863 (Folder 119)
- Bishop, Joel Prentiss. Thoughts for the Times. Boston: Little, Brown, and Company, 1863 (Folder 120)
- Clarke, James Freeman. Discourse on The Aspects of the War, Delivered in the Indiana-Place Chapel. April 2, 1863. Boston: Walker, Wise and Company (Folder 121)
- Kelley, W.D. and others. The Conscription. Also Speeches of the Hon. W. D. Kelley of Pennsylvania on the Conscription, the Way to Attain and Secure Peace, and On Arming the Negroes. Philadelphia: Gratuitous Distribution, 1863 (Folder 122)
- Agnew, Daniel. Our National Constitution: Its Adaptation to a State of War or Insurrection. Philadelphia: C. Sherman, 1863 (Folder 123)
- Moody, Loring, Compiler. The Destruction of The Republic, and of All Constitutional Liberty, the Object of Rebellion. The Testimony of Southern Witnesses. London, 1863 (Folder 124)
- Kelly, Dickinson and Douglas. Address of Dickinson and Douglas. National Hall Philadelphia, July 6, 1863 for the Promotion of Colored Enlistments. (Folder 125)
- The Illustrated Pilgrim Memorial. National Monument to the Forefathers, 1863 (Folder 126)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Public Documents 34-38. Reports of the Guardians of the Chappaquiddic, Christiantown, Dudley, Natick, Mashpee, and Troy Indians, September 30, 1863 (Folder 127)
- Ben- Israel, Ephraim. Voix d’un Polonais Israelite En Faveur De L’independence De La Pologne. Bruxelles, June 1, 1863 (Folder 128)
- O’Brien, William Smith. Lecture on Poland. July 1, 1863. Dublin: Goodwin, Son, and Nethercott (Folder 129)
- Manifeste Du Comite Central Franco-Polonais De France Et Addresses. Paris: 17 to 19, 1863 (Folder 130)
- Dangin, Paul Thoreau. La Pologne Et Les Traites De Vienne. Paris, 1863 (Folder 131)
- Hermann, Maurice. Le Soulevement De La Pologne. Paris: Libraire-Editeur, 1863 (Folder 132)
- Rybinski, Le General.La Pologne et Lord Palmerston. Paris, 1863 (Folder 133)
- L’Empereur Napoleon III et La Pologne (fifth edition) Paris, 1863 (Folder 134)
- Owen, Robert Dale. The Future of the North-West in Connection with the Scheme of Reconstruction without New England. Philadelphia, 1863 (Folder 135)
- Pope, Samuel. The American War: Secession and Slavery. A Lecture. The Manchester Union and Emancipation Society, 1863 (Folder 136)
- A Savoury Dish For Loyal Men. Philadelphia, 1863 (Folder 137)
- Stille, Charles J. Northern Interests and Southern Independence: A Plea for United Action. Philadelphia, 1863 (Folder 138)
- Moody, Lording. The Destruction of Republicanism, The object of Rebellion: The Testimony Of Southern Witnesses. Boston: Emancipation League, 1863 (Folder 139)
- National Celebration of Union Victories. New York City: George F Nesbitt, 1865 (Folder 140)
- Hanson, Richard. Davies. Science and Theology: A Paper Read Before the Adelaide Philosophical Society. London, 1864 (Folder 141)
- Wells, David A. Our Burden and Our Strength, or, a Comprehensive and Popular Examination of the Debt and Resources of Our Country, Present and Prospective. New York: Loyal Publication, 1864 (Folder 142)
- Seward, William H. Remarks of Hon. Wm. H. Seward, on the Occasion of the Fall of Atlanta, Saturday, September 8, 1864 (Folder 143)
- The Constitution: Supremacy of the National Government Over the Several States of the Union, Constitutional Jurisdiction of the National Government Over Revolted States, and Fallacy of States Rights, Based on State Sovereignty. Document 9, November 1864 (Folder 144)
- Cole, Cornelius. Speech of Hon. Cornelius Cole, of California, on Arming the Slaves. Washington, D.C. McGill and Witherow, 1864 (Folder 145)
- Boutwell, George S. Confiscation of Rebel Property: Speech of Hon. George S. Boutwell of Massachusetts, January 19; 1864 (Folder 146)
- Spalding, Rufus. Confiscation of Rebel Property: Speech of Hon. Rufus Spalding of Ohio. House of Representatives, January 23, 1864 (Folder 147)
- Myers, Amos. Speech of the Hon. Amos Myers of Pennsylvania: On the Constitutionality and Necessity of a Draft, February 3, 1864 (Folder 148)
- Taylor, N.G. Relief for East Tennessee. Meeting at the Cooper Institute, Address of Hon. N. G. Taylor, Late Representative from East Tennessee. New York, 1864 (Folder 149)
- Loring, Charles G. England’s Liability for Indemnity: Remarks on the Letter of ‘Historicus’” Boston, 1864 (Folder 150)
- Conway, M.D. Benjamin Banneker, The Negro Astronomer. Reprinted from the Atlantic Monthly, London, 1864 (Folder 151)
- Taylor, Mrs. P.A. Compiler. Professor Huxley on the Negro Questions. London, 1864 (Folder 152)
- Anti-Slavery Society. The Humanity of the Confederates, or the Massacre of Fort Pillow. London, 1864 (Folder 153)
- Shirreff, Emily. A few More Words on the Chivalry of the South. London, 1864 (Folder 154)
- A Woman’s Example and A Nation’s work: A Tribute to Florence Nightingale. London, 1864 (Folder 155)
- Boutwell, George S. Speech of the Hon. George S. Boutwell of Massachusetts, upon the Bill to Guarantee to Certain States Whose Governments Have Been Usurped or Overthrown, a Republican Form of Government. House Of Representatives, May 4, 1864 (Folder 156)
- Allison, William B. Homesteads for Soldiers and Sailors in the rebellious States: Speech of Hon. Wm. B. Allison of Iowa. Washington D.C, May 4, 1864 (Folder 157)
- Johnson, Reverdy. Speech of Hon. Reverdy Johnson of Maryland, In Support of the Resolution to Amend the Constitution So As to abolish Slavery, 1864 (Folder 158)
- Colfax, Schuyler. Speech of Schuyler Colfax of Indiana, of his Resolution Declaiming Mr. Long of Ohio, an unworthy Member of the House, April 14, 1864 (Folder 159)
- Schenck. Remarks of Mr. Schenck of Ohio, in Reply to Mr. Fernando Wood of New York, In the debate on Resolution to Expel Mr. Long. Washington D.C, 1964 (Folder 160)
- Grinnell, Josiah H. Early and Modern Democracy Reviewed: Speech of Josiah H. Grinnell of Iowa, House of Representatives, Washington D.C, March 5, 1864 (Folder 161)
- Anderson, Lucien. Speech of Hon. Lucien Anderson of Kentucky on the Democracy of Kentucky and their Allies in the North, March 5, 1864 (Folder 162)
- Blow, Henry T. Speech of Hon. Henry T. Blow of Missouri, in Reply to the Charges of Hon. F.P. Blair and the Postmaster General, February 23, 1864 (Folder 163)
- Kelley, William D. Have Faith in God and the People: Speech of Hon. Wm. D. Kelley of Pennsylvania. Washington D.C, June 15, 1864 (Folder 164)